Keil Aloia

Seattle, WA 🔒 425-247-5697

Keil@keilovergames.com ≥

www.linkedin.com/in/keilaloia/ in

www.keilaloia.com

Passionate problem solver with 2 years of game development experience seeking to join a collaborative team where I can grow as a developer. Experience includes building a variety of different games and applications ranging from 3D Platformers to 360 Videos. Envisioned, designed, and led a team of 6 from conception to completion, playing the roles of lead developer, project manager, and game designer. The game, RepairBot released on 02/07/2019 in alpha in the google play store for the google cardboard platform.

Skills

- C#
- C++
- Oculus
- 3D math
- VR/AR

- Unity3D
- Unreal Engine 4
- Android
- Vuforia
- Git

Experience

AUGUST 2018 - FEBUARY 2019

Company Founder/Lead VR Developer & Project Manager /KeilOverGames, Sammamish, WA- RepairBot

- Administered deadlines and coordinated bi-weekly meetings with all team members of up to 6 people, consisting of Tech Artists, 3D Modelers, and Audio Composers
- Worked side by side with marketers and play-testers implementing user feedback throughout the creation process
- Oversaw technical requirements on the Artist and Programming side to meet cross-platform specifications to work on both Google Cardboard and Gear VR/Oculus Go
- Lead Software Engineer accountable for all code implemented within the project making extensive use of Unity3D and C#
- Designed and Implemented the core game loop system based on randomization and dynamically progressing through 3 stages of difficulty

JUNE 2018 - AUGUST 2018

VR Developer / Kaio Interacive(Contract), Puyuallup, WA

- Rapidly prototype Virtual Reality Experiences with project deadlines ranging from 1 week to 1 month to meet client expectations making use of Unity3D and C#
- Worked within OVR(Oculus) and GVR(Google) API to create virtual reality experiences
- Extensively used Unity3d's DOTween and TextMesh pro tools to enhance player immersion
- Created interactive world space UI/HUD designed around people who have never interacted with VR to create a friendly and instinctual player experience

- Developed a system to implement 360° videos and scaled resolutions based on mobile preference
- Used 3DOF locomotion controls to create multiple virtual reality experiences

OCTOBER 2016 - JUNE 2018

Product Associate / Microsoft, Bellevue, WA

- Lead customer interactions with multiple virtual reality systems (Vive, Oculus, Windows Mixed Reality)
- Hosted Microsoft Mixed Reality launch party collaborating with developers and hardware creators extensively
- Hosted and organized Major League Gaming tournaments with major prize pools such as an all-expenses-paid trip to the Superbowl
- Trained Co-workers on the advantages and opportunities virtual and augmented reality systems can bring to consumers and businesses
- Taught children JavaScript, Scratch, basic physics
- Taught office products to small business, and customers in a one on one setting
- Fixed and solved various problems to help fix customer computers in ample time

Education

AUGUST 2019

Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp / University of Washington, Seattle, WA

JUNE 2018

Advanced Diploma: Game Programming (C++) / Academy of interactive Entertainment, Seattle, WA

Verified clocked 1600 hours using C++ within Game Development

JUNE 2016

AA: Arts & Sciences / Bellevue College, Bellevue, WA

Applied through Running Start program becoming a full-time student through my Senior year of High School. A member of the inaugural group of students to study abroad at Kogakuin University, Tokyo, JP